Finding Aid for Tivadar Balogh papers, 1946-1998
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Drawings 1946-1993
  - Architectural Drawings
    - Fairmont Builders (Folder 14)
      - Coyote Creek, Okemos, MI June 29, 1989, Pencil on mylar; renderings; architectural drawings of floor plans, elevations, sections (Folder 15)
    - Field, Jr., Mr. and Mrs. Marshall J. (Bud), Residence, Lake County, IL June 11, 1965, Pencil on mylar and paper; sepia prints; renderings; architectural drawings of floor plans, elevations, sections, details (Folder 16)
    - Fisher, Mr. and Mrs. Tom, Residential Alterations, Ann Arbor, MI July 9, 1988, Pencil on vellum; design development drawings; floor plans (Folder 17)
    - Fontaine, Mr. and Mrs. A.P., Residence, Osceola Township, MI April 25, 1967, Pencil on vellum; sepia prints; design development drawings; renderings; architectural drawings of floor plans, elevations, sections, details; electrical and heating drawings (Folder 17)
    - Ford III, Mr. and Mrs. Walter B., Grosse Pointe, MI, Pencil on vellum; colored pencil on paper; blue-line prints (Folder 18)
      - Pool Pavilion April 25, 1961, Pencil on vellum; colored pencil on paper; blue-line prints; design development drawings; renderings; architectural drawings of floor plans, elevations, sections, details; electrical drawings (Folder 18)
      - Carport September 24, 1961, Pencil on vellum; renderings; floor plans, elevations (Folder 18)
      - Enclosed Terrace June 8, 1963, Pencil on vellum; colored pencil on paper; design development drawings; renderings; plans, elevations, sections, details (Folder 18)
    - Friends of Miller Woods, Fence and Parking Area, Plymouth Township June 30, 1992, Blue-line prints; architectural drawings of site plans (Folder 19)
    - Gallup, Mr. and Mrs. Charles A., Residence, Callawassie Island, SC February 21, 1989, Pencil on vellum and mylar; blue-line prints; sepia prints; renderings; architectural drawings of floor plans, elevations, sections, details (Folder 19)
    - Gasdick, Ms. Florence and Ms. Betty Ritzenhein, Gotfredson Road, Washtenaw Co., MI, Pencil on mylar and vellum; blue-line and sepia prints (Folder 20)
      - Residence February 7, 1969, Pencil on vellum; blue-line and sepia prints; renderings; architectural drawings of floor plans, elevations, sections, details; mechanical and electrical drawings (Folder 20)
      - Addition August 8, 1980, Pencil on mylar; blue-line prints; architectural drawings of floor plans, elevations, details (Folder 20)
    - Genesis of Ann Arbor Classroom Addition, Ann Arbor, MI July 29, 1977, Pencil on mylar; architectural drawings of floor plans, elevations, sections, details; mechanical and electrical drawings (Folder 21)
    - Gilbert, Mr. Elmer, Deck, Ann Arbor, MI July 13, 1983, Pencil on mylar; architectural drawing of floor plan and details (Folder 22)
    - Gotting, Mr. and Mrs. Karl, Residence, Okemos, MI, April 7,1988, Pencil on mylar; architectural drawings of floor plans, elevations, sections (Folder 22)
    - Grosse Pointe Club, Grosse Pointe Farms, MI, January 2,1963, Pencil on vellum; colored pencil on paper; sketches; design development drawings; renderings; architectural drawings of floor plans and elevations (Folder 23)
    - Growth Works, Renovation, Plymouth, MI November 30, 1978, Blue-line prints; architectural drawings of floor plans, elevations, sections, details; electrical and heating drawings (Folder 23)
    - Handball Courts undated, Pencil on vellum; mylar photocopies; rendering; architectural drawing of floor plan; electrical drawings (Folder 23)
    - Hanyi, Dr. and Mrs. Karl, Residence, Plymouth, MI March 26, 1983, Pencil on mylar; renderings; architectural drawings of floor plans, elevations, sections, details; electrical and heating drawings (Folder 24)
    - Heide's Flowers, Shop Addition, Plymouth, MI, June 19,1978, Pencil on vellum; blue-line and sepia prints; architectural drawings of floor plans, elevations, sections, details (Folder 24)
    - Holder, Mr. and Mrs. Kenneth J., Residence, Superior Township, MI May 4, 1973, Blue-line prints; architectural drawings of floor plans, elevations, sections; electrical drawings (Folder 24)
    - Holt, Mr. George (Skip) and Linda, Residence and Shop, Howell, MI January 18, 1988, Marker on vellum; Pencil on mylar and vellum; renderings; architectural drawings of floor plans, elevations, sections, details (Folder 25)
    - Jack, Mr. and Mrs. William S., Residence, Lodi Township, MI April 18, 1985, Pencil on mylar; architectural drawing of floor plan and elevations (Folder 25)
    - Jarvey, Mr. and Mrs. James, Addition, Canton, MI July 24, 1989, Pencil on mylar; architectural drawings of floor plans and elevations (Folder 25)
    - Jebe, Mr. and Mrs. Emil H., Addition May 7, 1980, Pencil on mylar; architectural drawings of floor plans, elevations, sections, details (Folder 26)
    - Johnston, Carleton, Restaurant, Plymouth, MI October 26, 1976, Pencil and photocopy on mylar; pencil on vellum; sepia-line prints; renderings; architectural drawings of site and floor plans, elevations, sections, details (Folder 26)
    - Litchfield Apartments, Williamston, MI January 19, 1990, Pencil and photocopy on mylar and vellum; blue-line prints; architectural drawings of floor plans, elevations, sections (Folder 27)
    - Library Design Associates, Inc., Plymouth, MI December 13, 1989, Pencil on mylar; architectural drawings of floor plans, elevations, sections, details; mechanical and electrical drawings (Folder 27)
    - Lochmoor Tennis Club, Grosse Pointe Woods, MI 1974, Charcoal, marker, and pen on vellum; colored pencil on paper; renderings; design development drawings of floor plans and elevations (Folder 28)
    - Lundy, James L., Residence May 8, 1970, Pencil on vellum; blue-line prints; renderings; architectural drawings of floor plans, elevations, sections, details (Folder 28)
    - Mac Lellan, Mr. and Mrs. John, Residence, Hammond Lake, MI undated, Pencil on vellum; colored pencil on paper; renderings; floor plan (Folder 28)
    - Malvin, Mr. and Mrs. Richard L., Residence, Ann Arbor, MI January 28, 1965, Pencil on vellum; colored pencil on paper; blue-line prints; renderings; architectural drawings of floor plans, elevations, sections, details; heating and electrical drawings (Folder 28)
    - Mercy College of Detroit, Detroit, MI, Pencil and photocopy on mylar; blue-line and sepia prints; colored pencil on paper (Folder 29)
      - Library Addition September 4, 1975, Pencil and photocopy on mylar; blue-line and sepia prints; blueprint mounted on foam core; renderings; architectural drawings of site and floor plans, elevations, sections, details (Folder 29)
      - Library Addition September 4, 1975 cont., Pencil on mylar; structural, electrical, and mechanical drawings (Folder 30)
      - Marian Hall Renovation April 17, 1985, Pencil and photocopy on mylar; renderings; architectural drawings of floor plans, elevations, sections, details (Folder 31)
      - Marian Hall Renovation April 17, 1985 cont., Pencil and photocopy on mylar; color and electrical drawing (Folder 32)
      - Marian Hall Renovation April 17, 1985 cont., Blue-line prints; mechanical and construction drawings (Folder 33)
      - Sciences Building June 6, 1977, Pencil and photocopy on mylar; colored pencil on paper-mounted on foam core; architectural drawings of site and floor plans, elevations, sections, details (Folder 34)
      - Sciences Building June 6, 1977 cont., Pencil on mylar; structural and electrical drawings (Folder 35)
    - Michigan Eye Institute, Canton, MI August 8, 1979, Blue-line prints; renderings; architectural drawings of floor plans, elevations, sections, details; structural, mechanical, electrical drawings (Folder 36)
    - Niblet, Mr. and Mrs. Lawrence J., Carport, Detroit, MI July 5, 1960, Pencil on vellum; renderings; architectural drawings of floor plans, elevations, sections, details (Folder 36)
    - N. Atlanta Legacy undated, Blue-line prints; architectural drawings of plans, elevations, sections (Folder 36)
    - Plymouth Stamping Division-Eltec Corporation, Plymouth, MI March 1, 1976, Pencil and photocopy on mylar; pencil on vellum; rendering; architectural drawings of plot and floor plans, elevations, details; structural drawings (Folder 36)
    - Plymouth Township, MI, Pencil on vellum; colored pencil on paper (Folder 37)
      - Administrative Offices October 30, 1961, Pencil on vellum; design development studies; architectural drawings of floor plans, sections, details (Folder 37)
      - Garage and Storage Building January 16, 1962, Pencil on vellum; colored pencil on paper; renderings; architectural drawings of plot and floor plans, elevations, sections details; electrical and heating drawings (Folder 37)
      - Santa's Icicle House, Plymouth Square 1960, Colored pencil on paper; rendering (Folder 37)
    - Prizlow, Mr. and Mrs. Alfred J., Residence, Kentmoor Subdivision, MI April 12, 1963, Pencil on vellum; colored pencil on paper; design development drawings; renderings; architectural drawings of plans, elevations (Folder 37)
    - Ramirez, Dr. and Mrs. Arcadio, Cabana, Ann Arbor, MI August 10, 1983, Pencil on mylar; architectural drawing of floor plan, elevation, section (Folder 37)
    - Reek, Don and Alexa Gordon, Addition, Whitmore Lake, MI September 9, 1993, Pencil on mylar; color copy; rendering; electrical drawing (Folder 37)
    - Renderings 1961-1994, undated, Pencil and colored pencil on paper; marker on vellum, blue-line and sepia prints (Folder 38)
      - Unmounted renderings 1961-1990, Pencil and colored pencil on paper; marker on vellum; blue-line prints (Folder 38)
      - Mounted renderings 1962-1994, undated, Colored pencil on paper, blue-line, and sepia prints mounted on foam core and cardboard (Folder 39)
    - Roosevelt Memorial, Washington, D.C. undated, Colored pencil on board; rendering; architectural drawings of plans, sections (Folder 40)
    - Saper Galleries, East Lansing, MI, Pencil on mylar; architectural and structural drawings (Folder 41)
      - Gallery August 21, 1985, Pencil on mylar; rendering; architectural drawings of floor plans, elevations, sections, details; electrical drawings (Folder 41)
      - Gallery Addition, with Henry Ofiaria, AIA March 2, 1998, Pencil on mylar; architectural drawings of floor plans, elevations, sections, details; structural drawings (Folder 41)
    - Seger, Mr. and Mrs. Craig, Residence, Honor, MI undated, Pencil and marker on mylar; blue-line prints; renderings (Folder 41)
    - Student work,1946-1952 and undated (Folder 42)
      - University of Michigan--College of Architecture and Design and Untitled 1946-1952, undated, Colored pencil and charcoal on paper and board; figure and still drawings; renderings, floor plans, elevations (Folder 42)
      - University of Michigan--College of Architecture and Design 1951-1952, Colored pencil on board; renderings sections (Folder 43)
    - Swenson-Gale, Residence and Barn, Lansing, MI December 31, 1983, Pencil on mylar; marker on vellum; renderings; architectural drawings of floor plans, elevations, sections, details; electrical and heating drawings (Folder 44)
    - Vogel, Carola, Residence undated, Photocopy on paper; rendering; design development drawing of floor plan (Folder 44)
    - Werner, Mr. and Mrs. Arnold, Residence, East Lansing February 28, 1989, Pencil on mylar; rendering; floor plan (Folder 44)
    - Wilson, Margaret, Residence September 7, 1983, Pencil on mylar and vellum; floor plan; elevation (Folder 44)
    - Zeleck, Mr. and Mrs. Brian (Folder 45)
      - Residence, Barton Hills, MI March 4, 1979, Pencil and marker on mylar; architectural drawings of floor plans, elevations, sections, details; electrical drawings (Folder 45)
      - Scottsdale, AZ July 29, 1981, Pencil on vellum and mylar; marker and colored pencil on paper; renderings; architectural drawings of floor plans, elevations, sections, details; electrical drawings (Folder 45)
  - Miscellaneous Drawings
    The miscellaneous drawings subseries contains records of Balogh's work for the Plymouth community, including the township seal and posters for the Plymouth Symphony. Drawings and designs in this series are primarily on vellum.
    - Plymouth Logo, Plymouth, MI undated, Print on mylar and paper (Folder 46)
    - Plymouth Symphony Performance Posters, Print on mylar